What visualization you use,
لا تعتمد الرسوم المرئية التي تستخدمونها
not only depends on what data types you're working with but also
فقط على أنواع البيانات التي تعملون معها ولكن أيضًا
on how many columns in your dataset you want to look at in a single plot.
على عدد الأعمدة في مجموعة البيانات الذي تريدون الاطلاع عليه في مخطط واحد.
If you were only interested in one column in your dataset,
إذا كنتم مهتمين فقط بعمود واحد في مجموعة البيانات،
this is called univariate analysis where the uni here stands for one.
هذا يسمى التحليل أحادي المتغير حيث ترمز uni إلى واحد.
Before we talk about comparing variables to one another,
قبل أن نتحدث عن مقارنة المتغيرات ببعضها البعض،
it's important that you know which plots to create for univariate analysis.
من المهم أن تعرفوا أي مخططات ستستخدمونها للتحليل أحادي المتغير.
For univariate quantitative data,
بالنسبة للبيانات الكمية أحادية المتغير،
both continuous and discrete,
كلًا من المتصلة والمنفصلة،
the most common plot to visualize the data is known as a histogram.
فإن المخطط الأكثر شيوعًا لتصوير البيانات يعرف باسم المدرج التكراري.
However, we could also use a Box-and-Whisker plot,
ومع ذلك، يمكننا استخدام مخطط الصندوق والمؤشر
a Stem-and-Leaf plot or what is known as a Normal Quantile plot.
أو مخطط الساق والورقة أو ما يُعرف بمخطط Normal Quantile.
If you were plotting one quantitative variable,
إذا كنتم تخططون متغير كمي واحد،
there are rare cases in which you might use a plot other than a histogram.
هناك حالات نادرة قد تستخدمون فيها مخططًا بدلًا من المدرج التكراري.
For univariate categorical data,
بالنسبة للبيانات المصنفة أحادية المتغير،
the most common plot is a bar chart.
فإن المخطط الشريطي هو الأكثر شيوعًا.
A bar chart is like a histogram but the bins are determined based on
المخطط الشريطي مثل المدرج التكراري ولكن تُحدد الخانات بناءً على
a set category and not based on a range that the chart creator can change.
فئة معينة وليس بناءً على نطاق يستطيع منشئ الرسم البياني تغيره.
Other common plots include pie charts, and pareto charts.
تشمل المخططات الأخرى الأكثر شيوعًا، المخططات الدائرية ومخططات باريتو.
Pareto charts are essentially just bar charts where
مخططات باريتو هي في الأساس مخططات شريطية حيث
the bars are in order from the most frequent to the least frequent.
ترتب الأشرطة من الأكثر إلى الأقل شيوعًا.
In manufacturing companies, pareto charts are used
في الشركات الصناعية، تُستخدم مخططات الباريتو
all the time to determine which parts have the most problems.
طوال الوقت لتحديد الأجزاء التي بها أكثر المشاكل.
If you are working with an ordinal categorical variable
إذا كنتم تعملون مع متغير مصنف اسمي
it makes more sense to use a bar chart.
فمن المنطقي أن تستخدموا المخطط الشريطي.
I personally don't care for pie charts.
أنا شخصيًا لا أهتم بالمخططات الدائرية.
I also always try to avoid
وسأحاول أيضًا تجنب
three dimensional plots as they can be misleading but we'll get more to this later.
المخططات ثلاثية الأبعاد لأنها يمكن أن تكون مضللة ولكننا سنستفيد من هذا لاحقًا